

Frontend Developer, proficient in Angular2+, seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Agile Methodology, Requirement Gathering, Project Management, Web Development, HTML, CSS, NodeJs, MongoDB



Current Designation: Technology Analyst Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

Current Company: Infosys Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Frontend Developer, Angularis, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Agile Methodology, Requirement Gathering, Project Management, Web Development, HTML, CSS, Nodejs, Javascript, Mongo DB

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Experience in working with Angular 2+ modules, services, templates, directives, services and dependency injection to create a SPA.

Mobile-first Responsive & Progressive Web Application Development.

Personalization, Accessibility & internationalization.

Experience in Developing User Interface (UI) Rich Web Applications, and Web Service Applications using

Front End/User Interface (UI) Technologies like Type Script, Angular 2+, Node JS, Object

Oriented JavaScript, Bootstrap, Media Queries, CSS Frameworks.

Good amount of work done on Reactive forms in Angular 2 and their Validations.

Experience in making Responsive Web Pages using Media Queries and Tailwind & Bootstrap, Angular

Material for styling applications.

Work Experience

Infosys as Technology Analyst - Frontend Developer Oct 2013 to Nov 2020

Wingspan (internally called Lex) is a gamified talent reskilling platform that helps organizations accelerate their talent transformation journey. Involved in working on Authoring tool and end to end development of a tool with following features:

- 1. A tool (channel editor) in wingspan, with plugin type architecture to inject whichever component is required, will be injected dynamically into the view.
- 2. It enables users to create responsive microsites/web pages without having technical knowledge of HTML CSS or JS that can be made available on platform once finished and published by user. It is a tool equipped with number of widgets to make use of in-house page framework, a component Library using Angular, to provide responsive design and styles consistent with the application's designs and styles.
- 3. 20+ widgets for editor and page framework, to enhance user experience and brought simplicity & ease to help users for creating complicated designs, using angular material to keep design and style consistent.
- 4. Reduced the design time of pages by ~50% by using an in-house page framework and converting them to widgets that can be easily used by users on tool that helped build ~200 custom dynamic pages for different clients and units.
- 5. Worked on different authoring tools (course, Module, collections etc.) available in application to

enable users to create content on platform.

- * Collaborated with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability Created quality mock-ups and prototypes.
- * Worked collaboratively with other designers to ensure a consistent, integrated brand perception and userexperience.

Infosys as Technology Analyst Oct 2013 to Oct 2013

Infosys as Technology Analyst Oct 2013 to Till Date

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2013

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Agile Methodologies	
OBJECT-ORIENTED programming	
Angular, Angular Material, Express.js	
TYPESCRIPT, JAVASCRIPT	
HTML, CSS, SCSS, Node	
Git, NPM	
Bootstrap, Jquery, Material UI, RxJs	
Mongodb	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time